DILSHAD QURESHI

CONTACT

- **** +91-891-7444-720
- ♠ Dshadq@gmail.com
- Gwalior, Madhya Pradesh

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.)

Madhav Institute of Technology and Science

2013 - 2017

Higher Secondary (10 + 2)

Padma Raje Govt. Higher Secondary School

2012 - 2013

Metriculation (10th)

St. George High School

2010 - 2011

SKILLS

- Content Writing
- Data Entry
- Scientific/Technical Writing
- Computer Literacy
- Problem-Solving
- Strong Communication
- Research and Development

PROFILE

Skilled content writer experienced in creating compelling articles and blogs that increased traffic on company's website. Professional data entry clerk who excels at prioritizing multiple tasks and inputting data into databases. Junior research fellow with three years' worth of experience in writing and publishing high quality research articles in peer-reviewed journals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Content Writer

May 2023 - July 2023

TheCoinRepublic, Bhopal, M.P.

- Published web articles and blog content about finance, Web3, and cryptocurrency-related topics that elevated visits of readers on the website.
- Created plagiarism-free and Al-free article content while adhering to the guidelines of the company.

Data Entry Clerk

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

PoojaEnterprises7 Pvt. Ltd., Bhopal, M.P.

- Entered data of client orders into MS-Excel sheets with speed and accuracy.
- Verified contact information in data files prior to entry to maintain transparency.
- Scanned and saved documents in the database to manage records of essential organisational information.

Junior Research Fellow

Aug 2017 - June 2020

National Institute of Technology, Rourkela, Odisha

- Conducted research on the formulation and usage of plant-based fat alternatives of cocoa butter in confection-based food products.
- Handled the responsibility of ordering and replenishing stocks of reagents and log entry.
- Leveraged interpersonal and communication skills to assist peers, graduate, and undergraduate colleagues on certain aspects of technical and laboratory skills.
- Worked both independently and in collaboration with peers and other field professionals to accomplish quality research.
- Conducted in-depth search, review, and analysis of new as well as historical literature to understand overall advancements in research findings and techniques.
- Proficiently wrote and co-authored more than 10 original scientific manuscripts for publication in peer-reviewed journals.
- Performed tasks such as preparing materials for technical reports, posters, and seminar presentations.

WORK SAMPLES

- Dilshad Qureshi, Haladhar Behera, Arfat Anis, Doman Kim, Kunal Pal, Effect
 of polyglycerol polyricinoleate on the polymorphic transitions and
 physicochemical properties of mango butter, Food Chemistry, Volume 323,
 2020.
- Dilshad Qureshi, Amit Kumar Nayak, Doman Kim, Samarendra Maji, Arfat Anis, Biswaranjan Mohanty, Kunal Pal, Polysaccharide-based polymeric gels as drug delivery vehicles, Advances and Challenges in Pharmaceutical Technology, Academic Press, 2021, Pages 283-325.